天呐  杀了我得了
Oh, god. Shoot me now.
不要啊
I'd rather not.
怎么了
What's up?
安森·克莱普被晋升为警监了
Anson Klemp has just been promoted to captain.
他会负责92分局
He's gonna run the 9-2.
安森·克莱普是谁  名字这么傻还不改吗
Who's Anson Klemp, and why hasn't he changed his name?
我们是警校同学
We went to the academy together.
他是你的死敌吗
And he's your sworn nemesis.
不  他是我朋友
No. He was my friend.
他很不称职吗
So he's grossly underqualified?
不  他很棒
No. He's great.
那问题在哪里
So, then, what's the problem?
在我
Me.
我们一起入校  一起毕业
We started together, we graduated the same year,
他要当警监了  我还是...
and he's gonna be captain, and I'm just...
全市最棒的凶案组探长
The best homicide detective in the city?
不  落后于人
No. Falling behind.
你知道你这叫什么吗  帕特森综合征
You know what you've got? Patterson syndrome.
帕特森综合征
Patterson syndrome?
对  每次我写出了一本畅销小说
Yeah, every time I write a bestseller,
帕特森能写六本
Patterson writes like six.
让我抓狂死了
It's maddening.
但跟他比较
But comparing myself to him
也不能让我写得更快
does not make me write any faster.
我想我就是以为
I guess I just thought that I would be
我到了这时能坐在领导层的位置上了
in more of a leadership position by now.
我也说不清
I don't know.
或许我不该离开华盛顿的总检察长办公室
Maybe I shouldn't have left the A.G.'s office in D.C.
但你不想为了配合他们而委屈了自己
Except you didn't want to compromise yourself to play their game.
我就是觉得
Well, I feel like
或许我该能做到更多
maybe there's something more I should be doing.
卡塞尔夫妇早啊
Hey, Castles.
被害人是亨利·格莱姆
Our victim is one Henry Graham.
午夜左右胸部中枪
Took a single GSW to the chest around midnight.
那肯定有人听到枪响吧
So someone must have heard the gunshot.
有目击证人吗
Do we have a witness?
事实上  有
As a matter of fact, yes...
那个跑步的人
That jogger right there.
他看到凶案了吗
Did he see the murder?
没有  但他跑近的时候
No, but the killer was still looking
凶手还在翻死者的兜
through the vic's pockets when he jogged up.
-我很惊讶他居然没被打死  -他也很惊讶
- I'm surprised he didn't get shot, too. - So is he.
她本可以控制他  却叫他跑
She had the drop on him but told him to run...
大概都跑出个人最好成绩了
Probably set a personal best.
是个女的吗
Our killer's a she?
亚裔女性  三十多  衣着不错
Asian female, mid-30s, well-dressed.
不像一般的抢劫犯啊
Doesn't fit the profile of a typical mugger.
她从被害人兜里
Neither does the stuff
拿走的东西也不符合常规
that she took from the vic's pockets.
她拿走了他的手机和钥匙
She made off with his cellphone and his keys
但没拿走钱包和两百块的现金
but left his wallet and 200 bucks in cash.
那么这不是一起简单的深夜抢劫
So this was more than just a late-night stick-up.
叫目击者跟速写师画张疑犯画像吧
Why don't we get the witness together with a sketch artist?
已经在办了
Already in the works.
听跑步者的意思
And to hear the jogger tell it,
那小妞相当冷静
this chick was cool as can be.
她可能是职业杀手
She may be a pro.
那么问题来了
Does raise the question...
亨利这么晚在这里做什么
what was Henry doing here so late at night?
等人
Waiting for someone.
鉴证组找到了
CSU found cigarette butts
跟他兜里的一样牌子的烟头
that match the pack in his pocket.
如果他的确在搞什么鬼
And if he was up to no good,
也不会是第一次了
it wouldn't be his first time.
他因重伤罪在埃尔迈拉蹲过监狱
He did a nickel at Elmira for aggravated assault...
几年前才出狱
Got out a few years ago.
他还穿着工作服
He's still got his work uniform on,
去迅捷拖车看看有没有人知道
so let's see if anyone at Go Quick Towing
-他怎么会跑来这里  -走吧
- knows how he wound up here. - Let's go.
我能告诉你他不是在办公事
He wasn't on the job, I can tell you that.
我们没接过那里的活儿
We didn't have any pickups out that way,
我也不知道他为什么在那里
so I don't know what he was doing there.
谁会知道
Well, who would?
他有亲人吗
Did he have any family?
没有
He doesn't.
好像连女朋友都没有
He didn't even have a girl, I don't think.
可怜人
Poor guy.
我真是缓不过劲
I don't know. I just... I just can't get over it.
亨利是我最好的司机
Henry was my top driver.
是个不错的家伙
Just a... just a real stand-up guy.
-即便他有案底吗  -我也有
- Even though he had a record? - So do I.
释放犯人找工作比较困难
There's not a lot of jobs out there for ex-cons.
但亨利脱离了过去
But Henry, he, uh, he was out of the life,
所以我给了他个机会  我从没为此后悔过
so I gave him a shot, and I never regretted it.
你知道他跟谁有矛盾吗
Did he have problems with anyone that you know of?
嗯  亨利每天都受到生命威胁
Oh, yeah. Henry got threatened every day.
是吗  谁威胁他
He did? By whom?
什么人都有
All kinds of people.
挥球棒的  动刀的  动枪的  都有
Waving bats, knives, guns... you name it.
等等  他不是拖车司机吗
Wait a minute. I thought that he was a tow-truck driver.
专门负责汽车回收
Specializing in vehicle recovery.
亨利负责回收啊
Henry was a repo man?
大伙儿可不喜欢
And folks aren't that excited
我们拿走他们的车
when we take their cars away.
那么他受到的威胁
So, these threats that he got...
有没有哪个来自亚裔女性
Did any of them ever come from an Asian woman?
我记得是没有
Not that I can remember.
但听我说  探长
But listen, detective,
我们遇到的一些人很生气
some of the people we deal with are pissed off,
但他们气的是银行  不是我们
but they're mad at the banks, not us.
我无法相信
I mean, I can't believe
会有人找到亨利杀了他
anyone would hunt Henry down to kill him.
但我们还是需要车辆被回收的人的名单
Still, we'll need a list of the repos.
嗯  好
Yeah. Sure.
等等
Wait a minute.
或许这事跟
Maybe this has something to do with
昨天午饭时发生的事有关
what happened yesterday at lunch.
怎么回事
What do you mean?
他像往常那样出去吃午饭
Well, he went out to lunch like he normally does,
他回来的时候  吓得不轻
and when he came back, he was all shook up.
-是什么事  -他不肯说
- What about? - He wouldn't say.
他班没上完就走了  招呼都不打
He left mid-shift, without a word.
他离开了车场  再没回来
And he left the yard, didn't come back.
我就再没见到他了
That was the last I ever saw him.
他午饭去哪里吃的
And where exactly did he go to lunch?
我不知道
I don't know,
但还有一件怪事
but there was something else he did that was strange.
我们负责车锁的人告诉我亨利
My alarm guy told me that Henry was asking
几天前曾问他要2013X5的警报码
for access codes to a 2013 x5 a few days ago.
这怎么了
What was strange about that?
我们回收清单上没有2013X5
We don't have any 2013 X5s on our repo list.
我问过亨利的同事
So, I spoke to Henry's colleagues.
他们都不知道他昨天去哪吃了午饭
None of them knows where he went to lunch yesterday
也不知道他为什么问起X5的警报码
or why he was asking for the x5 codes.
或许回收员其实是在偷车
Maybe our repo man was actually stealing cars.
他显然有这个本事
He clearly had the skill set.
可是其他所有人都说
Yeah, but from everything that everyone said,
包括亨利之前的保释官
including Henry's former parole officer,
也说他是个守法的好公民
he was just a stand-up citizen.
那也是因为他隐瞒了
Yeah, that's because he was concealing
他在偷车的事
his car-stealing ways.
连他的老板都说他是个独来独往的人
Even his boss said he was a very private guy.
没人知道  亨利把目标瞄准了那辆X5
So, unbeknownst to anyone, Henry sets his eyes on an X5.
他拿到了警报码
He gets the alarm codes.
可这是个致命的错误
But, in a fateful error,
他偷的这辆X5是属于这个女人的...
he steals the X5 belonging to this woman --
一个三合会杀手
A triad assassin.
杀手
An assassin?
真的  又来
Really? Again?
拜托  这次对的上
Come on. This time, it fits.
怎么对的上了
How does it fit?
他偷了她的车  她就把他杀了
He steals her car, and she kills him?
她为什么不直接向保险公司报告了事
Why doesn't she just put in an insurance claim and call it a day?
因为这并不仅仅是车的问题
Because it wasn't about the car.
亨利偷了这辆车之后
See, when Henry stole the vehicle,
他拿走了车里非常有价值的东西
he took something of value from the inside.
也就是那个杀手在他口袋里找的东西
That's what the assassin was trying to retrieve from his pocket.
那被偷的东西又是什么呢
And said stolen item was...?
低温核融合技术
Cold fusion technology.
基因工程改造过的超级病毒
A genetically engineered super-virus.
尚未公布的《哈利·波特》秘密手稿
Some secret unpublished "Harry Potter" manuscript.
其实你说的有一件事情还有点道理
Actually, one thing that you said does make sense.
只有一个
One thing?
那辆X5应该和亨利的死有关
The X5 might have something to do with Henry's death.
我要打电话给车辆报失部
You know what -- I'm gonna call auto theft
看看最近有没有报告失窃的X5
and see if there are any reported stolen X5s recently.
车主是个三合会杀手
From a triad assassin.
她才不是三合会杀手
She's not a triad assassin.
这个可不好说
We don't know that.
这真是太可怕了  亨利是个非常好的人
This is just so terrible. Henry was such a decent man.
真希望所有房客都能和他一样
I wish all my tenants were like him.
是啊
I'm sure you do.
女士  你见过这个女人吗
Ma'am, have you seen this woman before?
我...我应该见过
Well, I -- I believe I have.
这里  在这幢楼里
Here, in this building?
是的
Why, yes.
我们在大厅里擦肩而过
We passed each other in the hall.
她朝亨利的公寓过去了
She was headed for Henry's unit.
什么时候的事情
When was this?
大概就十分钟之前
Oh, about 10 minutes ago.
-十分钟之前  -可能更短
- 10 minutes ago? - Uh, maybe less.
她和亨利被害有什么关系吗
Does she have something to do with what happened to Henry?
女士  亨利的公寓是多少号
Ma'am, what's Henry's apartment number?
Uh, 517.
卧室
Bedroom.
把你的备枪交出来
Now hand me your backup weapon.
支援在此
Here's his backup.
放下枪
Drop it.
你最好想清楚了
You better think this through.
我们可是警察
We're cops.
我也是
So am I.
香港警局
Hong Kong P.D.
谁是这起案子的负责人
Now, who's the lead investigator on this case?
你离香港可够远的
You're awfully far from Hong Kong,
张首席调查员
Chief inspector Zhang.
手铐真的有必要吗
Are these handcuffs truly necessary?
你袭击了两名纽约警局的探员
You attacked two NYPD detectives.
我当时不知道他们是警察
Only because I had no idea they were police.
你是说  她把你俩的枪都夺走了
So, you mean to tell me she got both your guns?
你...你又不在场
Hey, you -- you weren't there.
她动作很快
She's fast.
真的  非常快
I mean, like, crazy fast.
根本没那么快
Please. She ain't all that.
可她还是夺走了你俩的枪
And yet she got both your guns.
这上面说你是属于
It says here that you are a part of
一个中美联合有组织犯罪调查组
a U.S./Chinese organized-crime task force
大本营在旧金山
based in San Francisco.
你在纽约做什么呢
What are you doing in New York?
探长  我们还是直奔正题吧
Detective, let's cut to the chase, shall we?
我不是凶手
I am not the murderer.
那你是不是总能找到尸体
So, do you always make a habit of finding dead bodies
然后拿走他们的随身物品
and relieving them of their belongings?
我认识亨利
I know Henry.
生前认识他
Rather, I knew him.
怎么认识的
How?
说起来很复杂
It's complicated.
他是不是和你的什么调查有关系
Was he involved in one of your investigations?
他是我的朋友
He was a friend.
我们好些年没见过了
We hadn't seen each other in years.
我们本来约好在纽约见面
We made plans to meet here in the city,
可他后来打电话说他来不了了
and then he called me and told me he couldn't come.
他听上去很害怕
He sounded frightened.
我问他发生了什么吗
I asked him what was going on,
他说他惹上麻烦了
and he told me he was in trouble.
-什么麻烦  -他不肯说
- What kind of trouble? - He wouldn't say.
我打电话给他  他一直不接
I called back. He never answered.
我很担心  就立刻飞过来了
I was worried, so I flew out right away.
那你是怎么会在犯罪现场的
How did you end up at the crime scene?
因为亨利不接我电话
When Henry didn't return my calls,
我就让旧金山的同事定位他的手机
I had a colleague in San Francisco ping his cell.
然后你就在公园找到他了
So you found him in the park?
我赶到时  他已经死了
When I got there, he was already dead.
我就拿走了他的手机和钥匙
So I took his phone and his keys,
自己开始了调查
and I began to investigate.
那你在案发现场时为什么不报警
And why didn't you call us from the crime scene?
因为我不想浪费时间
'cause I didn't want to waste my time
进行这样的谈话
having this conversation.
我的朋友被谋杀了
My friend has been murdered.
我得找出凶手
I have to find out who did it.
不  是我要找凶手
No. I do.
探长  我刚和运输安全管理局确认过了
Detective, I just got off with the TSA.
张首席调查员的飞机午夜才降落
Chief inspector Zhang's flight didn't arrive until midnight.
那正是亨利被害的时间
Which is when Henry was killed.
她肯定不是凶手
She couldn't have done it.
我现在可以走了吗
Now may I go?
只要你保证不再调查这件案子
As long as you promise that you're not gonna work this case.
我可无法做出这个保证
That's a promise I cannot make.
你们也没有理由继续拘留我了
And you no longer have cause to hold me.
首席调查员  考虑到各方利益
Chief inspector, in the interest of all parties,
也许你可以考虑和我们合作
perhaps you should consider working with us.
我想马上拿回我的私人物品
I would like my personal effects returned to me now.
瞧一眼这个
Take a peek at this.
这是张的个人档案
It's Zhang's personnel file.
她可不是一般的警察
She's more than just some cop.
等等  那个中美调查组...
Wait a minute, that U.S./Chinese task force --
她不仅在组里
She's not just on it.
她还是负责人
She's running it?
表彰  嘉奖
Commendations, citations.
我的天  她好厉害
Oh, my gosh, she is impressive.
是啊  纸面上
Oh, sure, on paper.
她对付莱恩和埃斯波西托的身手呢
What about the way she schooled Ryan and Esposito?
也只是纸面上的吗
Was that just on paper?
警监
Captain.
我考虑了你的提议
I've been thinking about your proposal,
我觉得我们合作确实有益处
and I do see the advantage of us working together.
提议还有效吗
Does the offer still stand?
当然
Yes.
那好
Okay.
那咱们就从这里开始吧
Then let's start with this.
你之前提到  亨利死前
You had mentioned that before Henry died,
去吃了午餐  回来时心情很差
he had gone to lunch and returned upset.
我在他口袋里发现了这张收据
I found that receipt in his pocket.
是唐人街的玉寺餐厅
From the jade temple restaurant in chinatown.
时间戳是昨天下午的
It's time-stamped yesterday afternoon.
不如你们三个去查查吧
Why don't the three of you check it out,
看他午餐时有没有出什么事
see if there's anything about his lunch
-可能会导致他遇害  -好
- That can explain why he got killed. - Okay.
我是卡塞尔
I'm Castle.
我们是搭档
We're partners.
其实  我们也是夫妻
Act... we're also married.
-有意思  -就是啊
- Interesting arrangement. - Yeah.
肯定会很有意思的
This is gonna be fun...
咱们这个"三人行"
This little threesome here.
我是说查案
Investigatively speaking.
我不想...我无意...
I don't want to... didn't mean to --
我不是想暗示...
I'm not trying to imply that...
说不下去就别说了
Quit while you're behind.
好
Yeah.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
您好  三位吗
Hello. Table for three?
不  今天不是来吃饭的
Uh, no, not today.
我是贝克特探长  纽约警局的
Detective beckett, NYPD.
你们是警察
You are the police?
我是谭咪咪  这是我的馆子
I'm mimi tan. This is my establishment.
有什么能效劳的
What can I do for you?
关于你的一位客人
We'd like to ask you some questions
我们想问你几个问题
about one of your customers.
不是随便一位客人  他是我最棒的主顾
Not one of my customers... he's my number-one customer.
亨利每天都来这里用餐
Henry eats here every day.
以后不会了  他被杀了
Not anymore. He was murdered.
太悲惨了
This is tragic.
昨天亨利来这里时
When Henry was here yesterday,
有没有说起有什么麻烦
did he say that anything was wrong
或是他招惹了什么人
or that he was having problems with anyone?
不  应该没有
No, I don't think so.
她
Her.
她昨天来上班了吗
Was she working here yesterday?
苏颖  她来了
Suyin? Yes.
我去跟她谈谈
I'll go talk to her.
我能在这里等吗
What if I just stay here and wait?
好
Uh, yeah.
苏颖
Uh, Suyin?
我是贝克特探长  纽约警局的
Detective beckett, NYPD.
我们想找你谈谈
We'd like a word.
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want trouble.
不  你不会有麻烦的
No, no, you're not in any trouble.
我们只是要问你几个问题
We need to ask you a few questions.
我什么都不知道  我得去干活了
I know nothing. I must work now.
她有事没吐出来
She knows more than she's letting on.
她似乎很怕跟我们说话
It's like she's afraid to talk to us.
可能只是怕你
Us, or perhaps you.
她的口音表明她是重庆人
Her dialect indicates that she's from the Chongqing region.
那里的警方很腐败
The police corruption is rampant there.
我去用她的方言跟她聊聊
Let me talk to her in her native language...
让她放松点
Put her at ease.
她是接手了你的问询吗
Did she just take over your interview?
是
Yeah.
她可非常优秀  卡塞尔
Okay, she's more than qualified, Castle.
知道吗  她曾是最年轻的
Did you know that she was the youngest officer
升任首席调查官的警员
to become chief inspector?
她的破案率在香港警方
She has cleared more murders
历史中首屈一指的
than anyone in hong kong P.D. History.
好吧  她很擅长自己的工作
Okay, so she's good at her job.
不仅如此
Not just that.
看看她丈夫
Take a look at her husband.
动作电影明星
Action-movie star.
好吧  我也是个稿酬不菲的小说家啊
Yes, well, I'm a highly paid novelist.
那她的孩子们呢
What about the kids?
可爱吧
Cute, huh?
我还见过更可爱的
I've seen cuter. That's...
拜托  别告诉我你在拿自己跟她作比较
Please, tell me you're not comparing yourself to her.
我们...
We're...
她说昨天出了点事
She said there was an incident yesterday.
有一位客人拒绝点餐
A customer refused to order lunch.
他说自己在等什么人
He said he was waiting for someone.
亨利到之前他一直在查邮件
Apparently, he just checked his e-mail until Henry arrived.
然后坐去了亨利那桌  随后吵了起来
He joined Henry at his table, and an argument broke out.
后来他终于走了  但走之前他跟亨利说
Then he finally left, but not before he told henry,
"你逃不掉的"
"You cannot walk away from this."
苏颖知道他们为什么吵架吗
Does Suyin know what they were fighting about?
不  她没仔细看他
No, she didn't get a good look at him.
她说他是白人  40岁左右
She said he was white, 40s,
中等身高  中等身材
Average height, average weight...
这里的无线网需要密码吗
Is there a password required for Wi-Fi?
不用  无线网是免费的
No. Wi-Fi is free.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
如果那人用手机连过无线网
If the man connected his phone to Wi-Fi,
路由器就会记下他独一无二的MAC地址
The router would have logged his unique M.A.C. address.
我们可以用来查到他的姓名
We can use that and track his name.
看到没
Did you see that?
她可能凭一个无线网标志就破了这案子
She might've just broken this case with a Wi-Fi sign.
好吧  是很了不起  你高兴了
Yes, yes, I'm impressed. Are you happy?
不  卡塞尔
No, Castle.
她跟我很像
She's just like me...
但比我更好
Only better.
我查了亨利在餐馆期间
So, I traced all the deviced that used the restaurant's Wi-Fi
所有连过那里无线网的设备
during the time Henry was there.
只有一个设备的主人
Only one is owned by a man
符合嫌疑人的描述
fitting our suspect's description.
迈克尔·格拉斯曼
Michael Glassman.
很好  我们可以发一份给苏颖看看
Good. We should send a copy of this over to Suyin.
已经给了  她确定他就是
I already did, and she positively identified him
跟亨利争吵的人
as the one Henry was having the argument with.
格拉斯曼有犯罪记录吗
Does glassman have a criminal record?
事实上  正相反
Actually, quite the opposite.
等等  这没搞错吗
Wait a minute. Is this right?
怎么了  这人是谁
What? Who is this guy?
他是个联调局探员
He's an FBI agent.
格拉斯曼探员
Agent Glassman?
我是贝克特探长
I'm detective Beckett.
这位是卡塞尔先生
This is Mr. Castle.
你好
Hello.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming in.
我们是一边的嘛  执法协作
Well, we're on the same team, right? Law-enforcement synergy.
纽约警方需要我帮什么忙
So, what can I do for the NYPD?
我们在调查亨利·格莱姆之死
We're looking into the death of Henry Graham,
希望你能为我们解答疑问
and we were hoping that you could fill in the blanks.
亨利·格莱姆
Henry Graham?
恐怕我没听说过这个名字
I'm afraid that name doesn't ring a bell.
就是这个人
Uh, this man right here.
你没见过吗
You don't recognize him?
不  没见过
No, I don't.
格拉斯曼探员  我们知道你们有过接触
Agent Glassman, we know that you had contact with our victim.
昨天在玉寺餐厅有人见过你俩
You were seen with him yesterday at the Jade Temple restaurant,
在一起  还在吵架
together, having a heated argument.
有人提供了假消息
Somebody gave you a bum tip.
我从没去过什么玉寺
I was never at any Jade Temple.
至少你的电话
Your phone was,
和一个符合你形象特征的人去过
along with someone who bore a striking resemblance to you.
几小时后  亨利就死了
And then, hours later, Henry ended up dead.
昨晚午夜左右你在哪里
Where were you at midnight last night?
相信我  贝克特探长  你不知道为好
Trust me, Detective Beckett, you do not want to go there.
还执法协作呢
Well, so much for law-enforcement synergy.
他直接就说谎说不认识亨利
He out-and-out lied about knowing Henry.
他和这件事绝对有关系
He's in this thing up to his bolo tie.
只是我们还不知道是什么事
Only we don't know what this is.
我去问问
You know, I'm gonna see
盖茨警监能不能和联调局沟通
if Captain Gates can talk to the Bureau.
也许她能问出点什么
Maybe she can shake some info loose.
你呢  有什么线索吗
How about you? Do you have anything?
是有  但我还不确定这能证明什么
Uh, yeah, but I'm not quite sure what to make of it yet.
实验室在亨利的鞋底发现了
The lab found a phenol-formaldehyde resin
苯酚甲醛树脂
on the bottom of henry's shoes.
甲醛  尸体防腐剂里那种吗
Formaldehyde? Like for embalming?
没错  尸体防腐  电路板
Yeah, for embalming, making circuit boards,
织物处理  作用很多
treatment of fabrics -- all kinds of stuff.
他们认为他死前
They think that he must have
一定是去了什么用到了
been somewhere where that chemical was used
那种化学品的地方
right before he died.
也许他是在偷那辆X5时
Maybe he stepped in the formaldehyde
踩到了甲醛
right before he stole the X5.
他没有偷X5  我查了
He didn't jack any X5. I checked.
没有X5的挂失记录
There were no X5s reported stolen.
那他要报警码是要做什么呢
So what was he doing with those alarm codes?
而且如果亨利下午两点下班
And if Henry left work at 2:00 P.M.,
午夜死亡
showed up dead at midnight,
期间就有10个未知小时
he's unaccounted for for 10 hours,
那这期间他在哪
so where was he during that time?
他自己没车  我去查他的
Well, he didn't own a car, so I'll check the activity
公交卡和信用卡  看他是不是去了哪
on his metro and credit cards, see if he went anywhere.
我去询问他的邻居  看有没有人见过他
I'll circle back with his neighbors, see if they saw him.
好  有线索了通知我
Okay. Call me if you guys find anything.
好的
Yeah.
我刚刚还以为
For a second there, I thought
今晚就要耗在出力不讨好的乏味工作中了
I was gonna get stuck doing thankless grunt work tonight.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我们还没走呢
We're standing right here.
怎么啦
What?
对了  今晚
Tonight.
抱歉我忘记告诉你了
Sorry, um, I forgot to tell you --
我今晚要和张出去
I'm going out with Zhang tonight.
是吗
You are?
你真觉得这样好吗
Is, um -- you t-think that's a good idea?
挺好啊  我们毕竟一起工作
Yeah. I mean, we're working together.
应该更加了解对方
We should get to know each other better.
反正  别等我了好吗
Anyway, don't wait up for me, okay?
拜
Bye.
请坐  卡塞尔
Take a seat, Castle.
我们来跟你聊聊人生
Let me tell you a little something about life.
你刚才的反应  卡塞尔  就是低级错误
You see, what you did there, Castle -- rookie mistake.
我怎么了
What'd I do?
你不想让她去
You tried to stop her.
比如珍妮  她就有自己的女孩之夜
I mean, Jenny -- she's got her girls' nights,
而且我完全不介意
and I'm -- I'm totally fine with that.
在婚姻中
You see, in a marriage,
你必须要给对方留自己的空间
you have to give your partner some space.
好吧  莱恩
Okay, Ryan.
这是我第三次结婚了
Uh, this is my third marriage.
我想我知道该干什么
I think I know what I'm doing.
理查德
Rrrrrrrichard...
你为什么不想让她去
why don't you want her to go?
两位  我们都知道张德才兼备
Guys, it's no secret that Zhang is accomplished
而且贝克特也很钦佩她这点
and that Beckett admires her for that. E--
甚至是嫉妒她
Even envies her.
所以如果她们一起出去
So if they hang out,
我害怕会发展成诡异的竞赛
I'm just afraid it's gonna be some weird competition.
拜托  贝克特才不会那么做
Come on. Beckett would never do that.
对呀  哥们  这可是贝克特哎
Yeah, bro. This is Beckett we're talking about.
只是个女孩之夜罢了
It's a girls' night out.
才不会发展成竞赛呢
It won't be a competition.
不错啊
Not bad.
谢谢  其实我有些生疏了
Thanks. I'm, uh, a little rusty, though.
我也是
Me too.
我都六个月没进射击场了
I haven't been to a range in six months.
这就是六个月没练习的结果
That's after six months?
很难找到时间练习
It's hard to find time to practice
在香港  旧金山  海牙都很忙
with my duties in Hong Kong, San Fran, the Hague.
等等  你还在海牙工作过
Wait a minute. You work at the Hague?
在国际战争罪法庭
With the international war crimes tribunal.
相信我  其实也没传闻的那么好
Trust me, it's not as glamorous as it sounds.
但当你达到了一个顶峰
But when you reach the peak of a mountain,
就会开始寻找下个目标  不是吗
It's time to scale another one, right?
是啊
Yeah.
你身兼队长  妻子  母亲
So, uh, team leader, a wife, a mom --
不觉得忙不过来吗
isn't it a struggle to do it all?
所以不要试着兼顾  而是要找到平衡点
The trick is to not struggle, but to find balance.
一旦你觉得吃力了
The moment you think it's a struggle,
也就是失去平衡了
that's when you fall.
有一件事我不明白
You know, there's one thing that doesn't add up, though,
以你的身份
I mean, given who you are --
你想问我为什么会认识亨利吧
How Henry and I know each other --
因为我们来自不同的世界
Because we come from such different worlds.
没错
Exactly.
我父母是联合国
My parents worked as house staff
中国代表团的住院医师
for the Chinese Mission to the U.N.
所以我就在这里进了所公立学校
I ended up in public school, here in the city.
我当时不会说英语  总因此受欺负
I didn't speak much english, got bullied for it.
亨利总是帮我
Henry stood up for me.
我无法改变他选择的路
I couldn't stop what he became,
但我们一直是朋友
but we never stopped being friends.
不知怎么  你能做到这个
Somehow, the fact that you did this
让我觉得你更迷人了
makes you even more attractive.
是吗
Yeah?
你这话应该对张说
Well, tell it to Zhang.
这是她的成绩吗
This is her target?
十多次都是这成绩
And she has 10 others just like it.
说明她枪法很准  那又怎样
Well, so she's a good shot. Big deal.
她什么都很好
She's good at everything!
她事业有成
She's got an incredible career,
老公是电影明星  有完美的孩子
Movie-star husband, perfect kids.
她什么都厉害  她什么都有
She does it all, she has it all,
而且最重要的是  她长得很美
and to top it off, she's gorgeous.
是啊  没错
Yeah, she is.
等等  你认为她很美吗
Wait a minute. You think she's gorgeous?
我...
I...
只是同意你的看法
was just agreeing with you.
那我说之前你认为她美吗
Okay, but did you think it before I said it?
不...
No...?
天呐  卡塞尔  自从长了青春痘后
Oh, my god. Castle, I haven't felt like this
我就没有这种感觉了
since I had pimples.
我没有安全感
I'm insecure.
你不是没有安全感
You're not insecure.
等等  如果我不是没有安全感
Wait -- if I'm not insecure,
那你刚才为什么要那样说
then why'd you say what you just said?
好吧  你又来了
Ah -- okay, look, you're doing it again.
这是帕特森综合症
It's patterson syndrome.
我就知道你跟她出去是个坏主意
I knew it was a bad idea for you to go out with her.
不  卡塞尔  我只想知道什么是张的动力
No, no. Castle, I just wanted to see what made Zhang tick --
她是怎么得到今天拥有的一切
you know, how she achieved what she did,
这样也许可以帮助我提高自己
so maybe that could help me move forward.
凯特  你不需要她的帮助  你已经很好了
Kate, you don't need her help. You're doing just fine.
是的  但是当你到达一座山的顶峰时
Yeah, but when you reach the peak of one mountain,
难道不该翻越另一座山吗
isn't it time to scale another one?
那听起来像是张会说的话
That sounds like something Zhang would say.
你在引用她的话吗
Are you quoting her?
没有
No.
你把张想得太完美了
Look, you're idealizing Zhang.
你把自己跟一个
You're comparing yourself
根本不存在的她相比较
to a version of her that doesn't even exist.
她是个凡人  跟我们一样  也有缺点
She is a human, like the rest of us, flaws and all,
她并不是每次都会跳出来
not some infallible supercop
拯救世界的完美超级警察
who swoops in every time to save the day.
张刚找到可能会破案的线索
Hey. Zhang just got a lead that could crack this case.
你刚才说什么来着
You were saying?
我刚才在看亨利公寓大楼的
I was scanning surveillance video
监控录像
of Henry's apartment complex,
试图拼凑起他死那天的时间线
trying to piece together the timeline on the day he died,
然后我看到了这个
when I saw this.
那是亨利
That's Henry.
看时间  下午两点三十七分
Note the time -- 2:37 P.M.
就是说亨利离开回收场后  回了趟家
Meaning after Henry left the repo yard, he went back home.
不过他没有久留
Except he didn't stay.
五分钟后  他就离开了公寓大楼
Five minutes later, he left his apartment complex.
看接下来发生了什么
Watch what happens next.
在亨利·格莱姆死前  他被绑架了
Before he was killed, Henry Graham was kidnapped.
技术部门放大照片看清了车牌
Tech was able to pull the numbers off the license plate.
这辆越野车登记在"比利"威廉·希克斯名下
The S.U.V. is registered to a William "Billy" Hicks.
据我在缉毒队的兄弟说  这个人是狠角色
According to my buddies at narcotics, this guy's hard-core.
每年  他都会登上他们毒贩前二十的榜单
Every year, he makes their "Top 20" list for drug dealers.
但他们一直都没能抓住他...
But they've never been able to nail him --
主要因为他总让别人来做那些非法的事
Mostly because he has other guys do his dirty work.
我知道这个人
I know this man.
"比利"希克斯让亨利走上了犯罪之路
Billy Hicks started Henry on a life of crime,
他雇佣他做打手
hired him as an enforcer.
亨利就是因为他才进的监狱
He's the reason that Henry went to prison.
也许亨利也是因此才被杀的
Well, then he's probably the reason Henry was murdered.
但亨利不为希克斯工作  已有近十年
But Henry hasn't worked for Hicks in -- in almost 10 years.
为什么希克斯现在会找上他
Why would Hicks come after him now?
也许亨利知道的太多
Maybe Henry knew too much --
希克斯和贩毒组织的事
about Hicks and the organization.
这正是格拉斯曼在玉寺接近他的原因
That's probably why Glassman approached him at the Jade Temple --
联调局在立案调查希克斯
The FBI is building a case against Hicks.
格拉斯曼希望亨利揭发他的罪行
And Glassman wanted Henry to roll.
如果亨利拒绝的话
You know, if Henry refused,
那就解释了格拉斯曼为什么和他争吵
that explains why Glassman and he fought.
他是否拒绝并不重要
It doesn't matter if he refused.
像希克斯那样的人  如果认为亨利跟联调局交涉
If a man like Hicks thought Henry was talking to the FBI,
他会不择手段保护自己的帝国
he would stop at nothing to protect his empire
铲除威胁
and eliminate the threat.
在哪能找到希克斯
Where do we find Hicks?
他在皇后区经营了一家健身房
He operates out of a gym he owns in Queens --
奥唐纳拳击馆
O'donnell's boxing.
好的  我们走
All right. Let's go.
探长  等一下
Detective, wait!
我有话要跟你说
I need a word with you.
你不能追希克斯这条线
You can't go after Hicks.
为什么不行
W-why not?
总局直接下达的命令
Orders straight from 1PP.
他们有说原因吗
Did they say why?
只说那是联邦政府事宜
Just that it's a Federal matter.
我说对了  联调局在调查希克斯
So I'm right -- Hicks is being investigated by the Feds.
他们不希望我们搞砸他们的案子
And they don't want us screwing up their case.
长官  他可能是这案的凶手
Sir, he could be our killer.
他们知晓这一点  他们让我们等
They are aware of that. They need us to wait.
等多久
For how long?
等到可以落案起诉他
Until indictments come down.
到底什么时候可以起诉他
And when exactly do they expect these indictments --
几天  几周  还是几个月
Days, weeks, months?
我们不知道  但在那之前
We don't know, but until then,
上面下令让我们暂停对他的调查
we've been ordered to stand down from this investigation.
你是说...
What are you saying --
我的朋友死了  而我却什么也不能为他做吗
that my friend is dead and I can do nothing?
你是这个意思吗  贝克特探长
Is that what you're telling me, Detective Beckett?
公理何在
Where is the justice in that?
她说得没错
She's not wrong.
尽管我们不能接近希克斯
Look, even though we can't approach Hicks,
我们仍可以立案  收集他的罪证
we can build a case, gather evidence against him.
我们就从街头监控开始寻找
We'll start by combing street cams --
看是否能找到越野车
see if we can find out where that S.U.V.
带走亨利后去了哪里
went after Henry was taken.
我会派一队人去犯罪现场询问一下公园里的人
I'll send a team to the crime scene to canvass the park,
看是否有人记得曾看见过那辆越野车
see if anyone remembers seeing that S.U.V.
我们应该找张谈谈
You know, we should talk to Zhang,
看她还知道亨利和希克斯一些什么事
see what else she knows about Henry and Hicks.
张
Zhang?
伙计们  张从这里出去的吗
You guys, did Zhang circle back through here?
-没有  她从那条路走的  对吗  -是的
- No. She stormed off that way, didn't she? - Yeah.
你不会认为...
Oh. You don't think --
是的  没错  她去奥唐纳拳击馆了
Yeah, I do -- O'donnell's boxing gym.
她去找希克斯了
She's going after Hicks.
我去找她
I-I'll get her.
我应该对她负责
She's my responsibility.
如果你要找普拉提健身馆的话
If you're looking for the Pilates studio,
去街对面
it's across the street.
我要找你老板  在那  希克斯
I'm looking for your boss. There -- Hicks.
让开  托尼
Step aside, Tony.
别让女士这么不自在
Make a lady feel welcome here.
尤其是...
Especially someone as...
像花朵一样精致的女士
as lovely as this delicate flower.
有什么可以效劳的  怎么称呼
What could I do you for, Miss...?
张
Zhang.
我想跟你谈一个我们共同的朋友
I'd like to discuss a mutual friend --
亨利·格莱姆
Henry Graham.
抱歉  我没听过这个名字
Sorry. I don't know that name.
我可不这么认为
Oh, I think you do.
你不会想这么做的
You don't want to do that.
你会受伤
You might get hurt.
真是好笑  我刚好也想这么对他说来着
Funny. I was gonna say the same thing to him.
亲爱的  你不该这么做
Wrong move, sweetheart.
救命
Help me!
救我  救救我
Help me! Please! Help me!
张  后退
Zhang, step away!
别管我们  探长
Leave us, detective!
别让我再说一次
Don't make me ask again.
别以为这就完了  我要告你
Say goodbye, sister, 'cause I am pressing charges!
把这个疯婊子抓起来
Now arrest this crazy bitch.
也得先让我把你抓起来再说
Right after I arrest you.
凭什么
For what?
我们有你在亨利·格莱姆的公寓门口
We have a video of you abducting Henry Graham
绑架他的监控录像
outside of his apartment.
绑架
Abduct?
我们只是送他一程
We gave him a ride.
通过把他绑上车吗
By forcing him into your S.U.V.?
拜托  那只是个恶作剧
Come on, that was a gag.
我的手下只是在捉弄他
Okay, my boys were just... messing with him.
我们经常这么做  你去问亨利
We do that stuff all the time. Ask Henry.
那会很困难  因为他被你杀了
That's gonna be hard, seeing as you killed him.
等等
Wait.
亨利死了吗
Henry's dead?
我完全与那无关
Okay, I had nothing to do with that.
我只是在帮他
All I did was help him.
帮他做什么
Help him with what?
你不想对我说吗
You don't want to talk to me?
可以  那你跟她说去
Fine. You can talk to her.
好吧  听着
Okay, look.
他上周来找我帮忙
He came to me last week needing a favor.
帮什么忙
What kind of a favor?
这么说吧  他想要点东西
Let's just say he wanted something.
他想要什么
What did he want?!
可以假设地说吗
Hypothetically?
可以  那就假设
Yeah. Fine. Hypothetically.
这么说  只是举个例子
Let's say -- and this is just an example --
他想要500克可卡因
That he wanted half a kilo of coke.
他要可卡因做什么
Why would Henry need cocaine?
我们假设  在这个例子里
Let's just assume, in this particular example,
他说他想帮一个朋友
that he said he was trying to help a friend
脱离困境
get out of a bad situation.
那个朋友是谁
Who was the friend,
还有他们要可卡因做什么
and what were they gonna do with the coke?
也许他没有说  我也没有问
Maybe he didn't say, and I didn't ask.
也许我告诉过他他不该再掺和进来
Maybe I told him he shouldn't get back in the game.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
但他说这只是一次性的交易
But he said it was just a one-time deal.
你在说谎
You're lying!
-亨利绝不会贩毒  -等等  张
- Henry would never sell drugs! - Wait! Zhang! Zhang!
也许我们说的不是同一个亨利
Maybe we're talking about different Henrys,
因为我这个例子里说的亨利
because the one in my example
让我把那些可卡因分成小的定量
asked for it to be divided into smaller eight-balls.
探长  亨利以前在我手下干得很好
Look, detective, Henry served me well back in the day.
当货准备好之后
When the shipment was ready,
我是去接他  而不是绑架
I had him picked up, not abducted.
我把他需要的可卡因给了他
I gave him the coke he needed.
他很感激
He was so grateful,
他甚至告诉我联调局的人在监视我的地盘
he even told me about the Feds watching my place,
他们上周看到他离开这里
how they saw him leave here last week,
想通过他举报我
and they tried to get him to roll on me.
当然  这都是假设
Hypothetically, of course.
那是我最后一次有他的消息
And that was the last I've heard of him.
假设你说的都是实话
Let's just say that you're telling the truth.
他有没有告诉你拿了毒品后要去哪
Did he tell you where he was going with the drugs?
没有
No.
但我的手下送他回城时
But when my boys took him back to the city,
他没有回家
he didn't go home.
他想去53大道和第一大道的路口
He wanted out on 53rd and 1st.
莱恩  希克斯有可能没说实话
Yeah, Ryan. Look, Hicks could be lying about everything.
我们还是得派侦察队
We still got to send a patrol
排查53大道和第一大道附近  以防万一
to canvass 53rd and 1st, just in case.
寻找目击证人  谢谢
Yeah. Look for witnesses. Thanks.
他们还得调出那个区域的交通监控
They should also pull traffic-camera footage of the area.
你没资格再发号施令了
That is not your call -- not anymore.
你在想些什么
What the hell were you thinking?
我做了我该做的
I did what I had to!
一点都不考虑联邦调查局  纽约警局以及我
Without any regard for the Feds, for the NYPD, for me.
这就是你说的平衡吗
Is that what you call being balanced?
你想知道什么叫平衡吗
Okay, you want to know about being balanced?
我丈夫和我分居了
My husband and I are separated!
我也没尽到母亲的责任
I am not the mother I should be!
你觉得我是了不起的警察  我什么都有
You think I'm this amazing cop, that I have it all together,
可实际上我不是那样
but I don't!
亨利的死是我造成的
I'm the reason that Henry's dead!
你在说什么
What -- what are you talking about?
前几周他给我打了电话
He called the other week.
他留了一条信息
He left a message saying that...
说他需要我的帮助
...he needed my help.
我觉得那不是很重要
I didn't think it was important,
所以没有马上回电话
so I didn't call him back right away,
当我给他打电话时  已经晚了
and when I did, it was too late.
他说没有人可以帮他了
He told me no one could help him anymore.
所以你才会搭上那架飞机
That's why you hopped on that plane?
从小到大  亨利总是为我着想  帮助我
Growing up, Henry was always there for me,
保护我
protecting me.
可当他需要我时  我却忙不过来
And when he needed me, I was too busy.
我总是忙得没时间
I am always too busy
去做那些真正重要的事情
for everything that really matters.
所以我必须这么做
That's why I need to do this
不仅为亨利也为我自己
not just for Henry, for me.
谁打来的
Who is it?
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
当然是你的错
It sure is.
我要进去  她不该为此承担过错
I'm going in. She shouldn't take the blame for it.
如果她不想承担  她是不会这么做的
She wouldn't take it if she didn't want to.
相信我  贝克特在承担
Believe me, Beckett has plenty of experience
别人干的蠢事这方面颇有经验
taking a bullet for other people doing stupid things.
她和我结婚了
Hell, she's married to me.
但你们这些超级警察得聚团  对吗
But, uh, you supercops need to stick together, right?
怎么了
What happened?
我告诉她你离开时
Uh, I told her that you left
并不知道希克斯在我们的调查范围之外
before you knew Hicks was off-limits.
她相信你吗
Did she believe you?
她选择相信我
She chose to believe me.
谢谢你  探长
Thank you, detective.
谢我的最好方式
Well, the best way to thank me
就是帮助我们破案
is to help us solve the case.
我们在排查时找到了一点线索
Hey. So, we got a hit off that canvass.
他们找到一个小贩
Unis -- They found a street vendor
在53大道和第一大道的街角工作
who works near the corner of 53rd and 1st
看见亨利在遇害当天在一个住宅停车库
Who saw Henry loitering around a residential parking garage
附近徘徊
the day of the murder.
鉴于亨利是回收人
Seeing that Henry was a repo man.
我们联系了楼管
we contacted the building manager
拿到了停在那的车辆名单
to get a list of all the vehicles that park there.
其中一辆就是2013款宝马X5
And one of them was a 2013 x5.
亨利要找的就是它的报警码
Those alarm codes that Henry requested.
车是谁的
Who owns the car?
这位  杰弗瑞·沃德罗
This guy -- Jeffrey Wadlow.
是个富有的房产开发商
He's a wealthy businessman in property development
曾有过毒品指控
with a history of drug charges.
他的高能律师总有办法让他脱罪
That his high-powered attorneys always got dismissed.
直到前几天
Until the other day,
警方接到匿名线报称
because after receiving an anonymous tip to the police
沃德罗在贩毒  他们让他靠边停车
that Wadlow was selling drugs, they pulled him over
然后在他车里查获了500克可卡因
and found half a kilo of cocaine
分成小的定量
separated out into eight-balls stashed inside the car.
那就是说亨利没有在贩毒
That means Henry wasn't selling drugs.
而是嫁祸给别人
He was planting them.
对  但为什么
Yeah, but why?
亨利和沃德罗之间有什么关联吗
Is there a connection between Henry and Wadlow?
没找到
Not that we could find.
沃德罗现在在哪
Where's Wadlow now?
在中央监室
Central booking,
等待贩毒重罪指控的传讯
waiting arraignment for felony distribution charges.
亨利·格莱姆是谁
Who the hell is Henry Graham?
得了吧  沃德罗先生
Come on, Mr. Wadlow.
我已让警探们去彻查
I've got detectives digging into your life
你们俩之间的关系了
looking for ties between the two of you,
如果你说不认识亨利
And it's going to be worse for you
但我们查出你认识他  你就惨了
if you say you don't know Henry and we find out you do.
但我不认识他
But I don't know him.
那他为什么要把毒品放到你车里
So why would he plant drugs in your car?
太好了
Yes!
我跟警察说了有人陷害我
I told the cops they were planted.
终于有人信了
Finally, someone who believes me!
慢着  你们既然知道是他做的
Hey, hey, if you know it was this guy,
那我不就可以出去了吗
then I can get out of here, right?
可你买凶谋杀亨利
Not when you reached out and hired someone
这帐还没算
to murder Henry.
谋杀
Murder?!
我从来没杀过人
I-I would never have someone killed,
更何况是素昧平生的人
I-I -- especially someone I've never even seen before.
如果你不认识亨利
If you don't know Henry,
那他为什么要陷害你
then why would he try to frame you?
我怎么知道
I have no idea.
可能是有人教唆他这么做的
Maybe somebody put him up to it.
-比如谁  -我不知道
- Like who? - I don't know.
或许是有人
Maybe somebody who --
看不惯我做生意的方式
somebody who doesn't like the way I do business --
竞争对手  可能
A competitor, maybe.
沃德罗先生  如果你入狱  谁最获利呢
Who stands to gain by you going to prison, Mr. Wadlow?
好多好多人
A whole lot of people.
沃德罗的谋杀嫌疑洗清了
Wadlow's in the clear for the murder.
亨利死亡时他正被关押着
He was locked up at the time of the death.
他会不会在拘留期间买凶呢
Could he have ordered Henry's execution while detained?
他打了一通电话  给他的律师
Uh, he made one phone call -- to his lawyer.
在亨利死之前
And he didn't manage to get through
电话一直没接通
until Henry was already dead.
贝克特  我们梳理了
Yo, Beckett, we were combing through
沃德罗的业务往来  发现了一些
Wadlow's business dealings, and we came across something
可能和案件有关的信息
that might be connected to our case.
过去的半年里
Over the past six months,
沃德罗一直在购入不动产
Wadlow's been buying up real estate
以便他在唐人街进一步开发
for his next new development in Chinatown,
每次他出价
and each time he did,
都能高于同类对手公司
he outbid the same rival company.
VCN控股公司  然而VCN的女老板
VCN holdings -- and the woman who runs VCN
正好拥有一家小餐厅
also happens to own a little restaurant
玉寺
called the Jade Temple.
谭咪咪是幕后主使
Mimi Tan is behind this?
对  餐厅是她那些生意中的一个
That's right -- it's one of dozens of businesses she owns,
并不是所有生意都蒸蒸日上
and not all of them are on the up-and-up.
有组织犯罪科说
Organized crime tells us
传闻谭咪咪和贩卖人口有关联
that Mimi Tan's rumored to be linked to human trafficking.
她雇佣非法劳工
She staffs her businesses with illegals
通过三合会从中国偷运人口
that she smuggles from China via a network of triads.
但她现在想要洗白
But now she's looking to go legit,
把开发唐人街
and shes sees the Chinatown development
作为其社会地位的筹码
as her ticket to respectability.
所以亨利每天
So the fact that Henry was eating
去她的餐厅用餐并不是巧合
at her restaurant every day is not a coincidence.
咪咪一定是说服了她的"头号顾客"
Mimi must have persuaded her "Number-one customer"
把毒品栽赃给沃德罗以铲除竞争对手
to plant those drugs on Wadlow to eliminate the competition.
然后  一旦亨利完成使命
And then, once Henry completed his task,
咪咪就把他铲除了
Mimi had him eliminated.
但是  怎么证明这些呢
Only, how do we prove it?
我们得找出点有力证据
We're gonna need something stronger
不仅仅是特价午餐
than just the lunch special.
就等你问了
Well, ask and ye shall receive.
还记得我们在亨利鞋底找到的
Do you remember that phenol-formaldehyde resin
苯酚甲醛树脂吗
that the lab found on the bottom of Henry's shoes?
它可能来自一家制衣厂
Well, it might have come from a garment factory
距离亨利中枪的公园只有几个街区
a few blocks away from the park where Henry was shot.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
因为那家工厂是谭咪咪的
Because that factory is owned by Mimi Tan.
又见面啦
Hello again.
这回是来享用晚餐吗
Joining us for dinner this time, I hope?
不  不是今晚
Uh, no, not tonight.
其实我们是想
Actually, we were hoping
你能协助我们
that you could help us a little more
调查亨利的凶案
with Henry's murder investigation.
当然可以  我能做些什么
Of course -- whatever I can do to help.
杰弗瑞·沃德罗  你认识他吗
Jeffrey Wadlow -- do you know him?
他是本地开发商
He's a local developer.
我知道他  很不择手段的一个人
I know of him -- very unscrupulous.
或许如此
Perhaps so.
几天前他因贩毒被捕了
He was arrested for drug charges the other day.
他运气真不好
How unfortunate for him.
所以你就走运了
Oh, and how fortunate for you.
沃德罗入狱
Wadlow goes to prison,
他近期所有的不动产交易都黄了
all his recent real-estate deals fall apart.
你的公司就有机会接盘
Making room for your company to swoop in
买下许多唐人街的产业
and buy numerous Chinatown properties.
这跟亨利的死有什么关系
And what does this have to do with Henry's death?
你让亨利把毒品放到沃德罗的车里
You enlisted Henry to plant those drugs in Wadlow's car
帮你铲除竞争对手
to get rid of your competition.
-太荒谬了  -是吗
- That's absurd. - Is it?
我们在亨利的鞋底发现了
We found phenol-formaldehyde resin
苯酚甲醛树脂
under Henry's shoe --
和你那家制衣厂用的是同种材料
the same kind that's used at your garment factory
就在犯罪现场附近
near the crime scene.
我们找了几个工人询问
We talked to several of your workers
他们看到在亨利被杀当晚
who saw you with Henry at the factory
你和他在工厂见面
the night he was murdered.
我现在就要见我的律师
I want to talk to my lawyer now.
你为什么这么做
Why did you do it?
过河拆桥  是吗
To tie up loose ends? Is that it?
我不会再说一句话  直到...
I'm not saying another word until --
是你  是你杀了他
It was you! You killed him!
等等
Wait! Hey!
亨利来这不是为了吃东西
Henry didn't come here for the food.
他来这里是为了你
He came here for you.
他本来要带我离开的  还我自由
He was going to take me away -- free me!
可你杀了他
And you kill him!
我没有杀亨利
I did not kill Henry.
你说谎
You lie!
你说他来还你自由什么意思
What do you mean, he came here to free you?
我欠把我偷渡来的人很多钱
I owe much money to the smugglers who bring me here.
她还清了欠款
She buy my debt.
我要在这打工很多年还债
I work here to pay it off for years.
你胡说
That's not true.
然后你见到了亨利
And then you met Henry.
他想跟我一起生活
He want us to start a life together.
他找咪咪想赎回我
He went to Mimi to pay my debt --
四万美元
$40,000.
亨利没那么多钱
And Henry didn't have that kind of cash,
于是你们就苏颖的自由达成了另一个协议
So you made a different agreement for Suyin's release.
你让亨利栽赃沃德罗换取她的自由
You had Henry frame Wadlow for her freedom.
他为我那么做了
He did that for me?
那他为什么说
That's why he say
让我那晚在公园见他
for me to meet him at the park that night.
他说他有好消息
He say he would have good news.
等等
W-w-w-wait.
那晚他在公园是等你
So you were the one he was waiting for at the park?
不
No.
我本该去的  但亨利打电话给我
I was supposed to, but Henry phone me.
他让我不要来
He say not to come.
他爽约了
He canceled?
他告诉你原因了吗
Did he tell you why?
我没跟他讲话
I did not speak to him.
他打到这里留了言
He call here and left a message.
苏颖  谁告诉你这条留言的
Suyin, who gave you that message?
谢谢  吴梅
Thanks, Mei Wu.
我们只需理清一些细节
We just need to clear up a few details.
用不了多久
This shouldn't take too long.
当然
Of course.
亨利是个好人
Henry was a good man.
是的
Yes. He was.
苏颖告诉我们
So, Suyin told us
亨利被杀那晚  你在
that you were working at the restaurant
餐馆当班
the night that Henry was killed.
她说你告诉她一条留言
She said that you gave her a message.
-是这样吗  -是的
- Is that correct? - Yes.
不好意思  我做错了什么吗
I'm sorry. Did I do something wrong?
是的
I'll say so.
你骗了她
You lied to her,
就像你现在这样糊弄我们
just like you're lying to us right now.
我们查看亨利的通话记录
We checked Henry's phone records.
他没给餐馆打过电话
He never called the restaurant.
他肯定是用了别的电话
He must have used a different phone.
我跟他交谈过
I did speak with him.
当然
Yeah, of course you did --
当你在公园跟他对质的时候
When you confronted him at the park.
什么...公园
What...park?
你的地铁卡显示
Your metro card shows
在亨利被杀的时间区内
that you entered the subway across the street
你过街进了地铁站
during henry's time-of-death window.
苏颖跟我们说了你们的友情
Suyin told us about your friendship --
一起长大
How you grew up together,
一起来到这里  苦不堪言
how you both came here, how hard it was.
你们都欠了谭咪咪的债
How you both owe a debt to Mimi Tan.
但那一切要被改变了
But that was all about to change.
你意识到亨利要还清苏颖的债
You realized Henry was gonna clear Suyin's debt
把她从你身边夺走
and take her away from you.
你容不得那种事发生
And you could not allow that to happen.
求你们
Please.
我没做错事
I did nothing wrong.
鉴证组在你公寓的衣服上发现了微量血渍
CSU recovered blood micro-spray on clothes found in your apartment.
跟亨利的血匹配
That blood matches Henry's.
不不  搞错了
No, no. This is a mistake.
苏颖是我唯一的朋友
Suyin is all I have here,
她要丢下我
and she was going to leave me!
我得做点什么
I had to do something!
我别无他法
I had to!
吴梅  你因谋杀亨利·格莱姆而被捕
Mei Wu, you're under arrest for the murder of Henry Graham.
苏颖怎么样了
How's Suyin doing?
她很坚强
She's strong.
会没事的
She'll be all right.
还是有点好消息
So, um, a bit of good news.
我跟移民局的人谈过
I-I spoke with immigration,
苏颖如果在谭咪咪的案子中作证
and in exchange for Suyin testifying against Mimi Tan,
他们会给她提供救助
they are going to grant her asylum.
她会留在美国
She's gonna be allowed to stay in the U.S. --
但这次她是自由的
But free this time.
如亨利所愿
Just as Henry wanted.
下一步  你要做什么
So, what are you gonna do now?
不知道
I don't know.
接着之前的事情  收拾残局
Pick up where I left off. Pick up the pieces.
找到自己的平衡
Try to find my balance.
做起来不如说着这么容易
It's easier said than done.
祝好运  调查员
Good luck, Inspector.
谢谢你  凯特
Thank you, Kate.
为你所做的一切
For everything.
你认为张会跟你保持联系吗
So, you think you and Zhang will stay in touch?
希望如此
I hope so.
我们超级女警应该聚团
I mean, us supercops need to stick together.
你不是在打破我的《水果忍者》纪录吧
You're not trying to break my high score on Fruit Ninja, are you?
没有  我在写将来的头等大事清单
No, I'm writing up a list of priorities for my future.
要翻越的新山峰
New mountains to climb.
会是什么呢  富士山  乞力马扎罗山  珠峰
Well, what's it gonna be -- Fuji, Kilimanjaro, Everest?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
我喜欢所做的事
I mean, I love what I do,
但感觉我必须找到新的挑战
but I feel like I have to find a new challenge.
就跟你写到乏味
It was kind of like when you
写死德里克·斯道姆一样
killed off Derrick Storm 'cause you were bored.
是啊  结果很赞呢
Ah, yeah. Look how that turned out.
是啊
Yeah.
不管接下来如何
Well, whatever is next,
我不希望依靠在我的头等大事上有所妥协
I don't want to have to compromise my priorities
而翻过山峰  我不想因为
to get there, and I never want to be guilty
错过最重要的而悔恨莫及
of leaving behind what matters most.
永远在你身边的  你怎会错过
You cannot leave behind what is always at your side.
这话你刚刚想到的吗
Did you just make that up?
是的  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
你比帕特森厉害多了
You're so much better than Patterson.